❖ Nash Worth (pro pseudonym)

alpinefalcon@protonmail.com Discord: spazeFalcon#5533 Remote, Metaverse



JavaScript/React/Lead/Mentor ❖

GitHub: github.com/netcinematics LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/nworth4/ Portfolio: https://linktr.ee/spazefalcon

Talented and Highly-Experienced Senior Developer

Ten years, FULLSTACK, enterprise experience. Team Lead, excellent SOFT-SKILLS, including MENTORSHIP, creative, design, visualization, and system architecture. Many languages, Mobile Apps, APIs, frameworks, libraries, modules, design patterns, polyglot, best-practice, cross-platform, solutions and experiences.

- Strong **TECHNICAL-SKILLS**, experienced in *modern Front-End best-practices*. With public-facing enterprise experience. Attention to detail, Testing, Continuous Integration.
- Talented **CREATIVE** and **VISUAL-SKILLS**: *UX/UI, Web Design*, Illustration, Audio/Video, 2D/3D, content-production, slide-decks, collaborations, visualizations, and infographics.
- Excellent **TEAM-SKILLS**: inspiration with good humor, enthusiasm and passion for code quality, and the ability to deliver complex technical solutions quickly and smoothly.
- Pro **TEAM-LEAD** and **MENTOR** to hundreds of graduates, colleagues, and contacts. Nash inspires SUCCESS, with kindness and passion for hard work and excellent *soft-skills*.

MOTTO, deliver ahead of schedule, above expectation, exact to requirement, and as a perfect-fit in TEAM.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, ES6, React, NodeJS, API, Apps, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, NextJS, TailwindCSS, NPM, GitHub, VS Code, Front-End: Web 2.0: Promises, Hooks, Async/Await/AJAX, Express, MongoDB, Knex, SQL, Web3, ethers, hardhat, remix, D3.js, WebGL, C/C++/Java/C#, MVC: Angular, jQuery, DOM, git, vercel...

SUCCESS STORIES

Technical producer and creative content director: 2018 - 2023 at NetCinematics, led full life-cycle innovation of multi-media creative-content to production, curation, and promotion to successful launch targets.

Data Visualization for Cyber Security in SanFrancisco: 2017 lead data visualization developer in D3.js, creating sensitive information views to executive teams for various charts, graphs, timelines, and maps.

SAP Team Lead on eCommerce platform: In 2015 at SAP, led an international team to implement Angular Front-End with features like Coupons, Shopping Cart, and eCommerce Security best-practices.

Pushed OLYMPICS and SUPER BOWL to production: In 2014 at Dish Anywhere, coded the video slider mechanism and the gallery items for the Superbowl, Olympics, and major video streams. Also implemented the "four star" video favorites system, for the enterprise site of dishanywhere.com

Excellent Mentorship & Team Lead: Thinkful, ETHDenver TechStars, and DaVinci Institute, Nash has many years of SUCCESS working with CEOs CTOs, Founders, Innovators, Executive Teams students and colleagues. Ability to communicate clearly, professionally, and work well with any type of personality.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web3 METAVERSE ARCHITECT / Producer / Content-Creator

Boulder, Colorado 09/2017 – Present

NetCinematics

Thinkful

- Created JavaScript video pipeline with BabylonJS (WebGL), then minted as NFTs on OpenSea, Rarible others.
- Produced AR/VR animations in Virtual Reality, and Web for creative content curation and social media distribution.
- Wrote Smart Contracts, in Solidity, for end users to interact dynamically on the BLOCKCHAIN and dApps on Web3.

FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT MENTOR

Online, Remote

08/2017 - Present

- Live coded React and JavaScript, with advanced topics like algorithms, hooks, promises, knex and database data structures.
- Flexibly adapted to any learning style and had much success collaborating with everyone to set and meet goals.

SENIOR CYBER-SECURITY DATA-VISUALIZATION

SanFrancisco, California

07/2015 - 02/2017

- Bay Dynamics
- Created custom charts, dashboards, and innovative cyber security data visualizations for CEO.
- Ability to take PATTERNS in the Data, and TELL THE STORY with CHARTS, ANALYTICS and Design Patterns.
- Built a gallery of visualizations for fortune 500 bank client, to visualize their threat assessment and take corrective action.

SENIOR E-COMMERCE - TEAM LEAD

Boulder, Colorado 10/2014 – 07/2015

SAP / Hybris

- Implemented major solutions like shopping cart, build system, tests TDD, code coverage and eCommerce coupons.
- Conducted standards, best-practice and security review for executives, by implementing helmet.js in nodejs.

SOCIAL-NETWORK - TEAM LEAD

Boulder, Colorado 05/2014 – 09/2014

gloo

- Angular lead for standards and best-practices for Social Media platform.
- Gamification, Masonry, API, and build systems.

ENTERPRISE WEB-VIDEO - TEAM LEAD

Boulder, Colorado

05/2013 - 05/2014

- Dish / DishAnywhere.com
- Delivered WEB VIDEO SOLUTION for the SUPERBOWL, OLYMPICS and Soccer finals of 2014.
- Hired team and instructed best-practices like GitHub and Agile Development Methodology and TDD code coverage.

ENTERPRISE WEB-FINANCE - TEAM LEAD

Denver, Colorado

FirstBank / efirstbank.com

02/2011 - 05/2013

- Lead major initiative of finance visualization, for mobile banking across Web, Tablets, and Phones.
- Created illustrations for the Marketing team for creative, (cool and funny) web design and UI/UX for user studies.
- Helped track security events with great synergy with the infosec team, and began a career interest in cyber security.

EDUCATION

B.S COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Graduation 2002

University Northern Colorado

- → Dean's List. 4.0,
- → Presidential Silver Scholarship Award.
- → Extended study in Artificial Intelligence and Natural Language Processing.

Professional Education: Encode Camp(2022), Alchemy University (2023), many conferences on: cyber security and best practices of visual design, Hero Journey story design, color theory, web design, system design and architecture. Professionally trained by multiple famous mentors.

ADVANCED EXPERIENCES: 3D Metaverse, AR/VR, AI, NLP, IoT, NFT, Blockchain and Web3. GIS, Data Visualization, Analytics, Performance Optimization, Cyber Security, Algorithms, Data Structures, Design Patterns, Mentorship, Team Leadership, Social Network Promotions, and many more.